<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Random | Victor Quinn]]></title>
  <link href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/categories/random/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://victorquinn.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-06T16:56:32-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://victorquinn.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Victor Quinn]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[inquiries@victorquinn.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Moving]]></title>
    <link href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2013/01/06/moving/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-06T15:47:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://victorquinn.com/blog/2013/01/06/moving</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ugh. Just seeing the word makes me cringe. The weekend after Christmas, I moved
into a new place. I am at once excited about my new home and the prospect of a
new beginning while frustrated at the ridiculous time sink it has become.</p>

<p>Things were not (for reasons on which I will not elaborate) working out at our
old place, so we packed up everything we owned and now have a new start in a
a new townhouse.</p>

<p>I sit here, surrounded by boxes and bare walls, having already spent an
untold number of days putting every one of my worldly possessions into boxes
just to remove them upon arrival at this new house, and knowing I'll spend many
more before reaching the end.</p>

<p>Things are good and I am overall quite happy, but if someone told me, "you will
have to stop all work on anything productive for the next 2 months while you
do nothing but pick your stuff up here and put it away on the other side" I'd
have told them to shove something somewhere where things aren't meant to shoved.</p>

<p>Instead of being a lot further along building <a href="http://scalesapp.com">Scales</a> I
have moved my stuff from over there to over here. &lt;sarcasm>Awesome.
&lt;\/sarcasm></p>

<p>The first few days here were exciting:
* Look at all the organizing I can do!
* Everything can be put in its rightful place
* Clean all the things!
* There are so many possibilities</p>

<p>But now that the honeymoon period has worn off, I'm left with a ton of boxes and
little motivation. I've put away and dealt with the fun things, all that's left
is the tedious boring stuff. I'll slog through it and my wife will no doubt help
keep me motivated but man is it a drag.</p>

<p>I. Hate. Moving.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
