<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Victor Quinn]]></title>
  <link href="http://victorquinn.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://victorquinn.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-06T16:56:32-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://victorquinn.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Victor Quinn]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[inquiries@victorquinn.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Moving]]></title>
    <link href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2013/01/06/moving/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-06T15:47:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://victorquinn.com/blog/2013/01/06/moving</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ugh. Just seeing the word makes me cringe. The weekend after Christmas, I moved
into a new place. I am at once excited about my new home and the prospect of a
new beginning while frustrated at the ridiculous time sink it has become.</p>

<p>Things were not (for reasons on which I will not elaborate) working out at our
old place, so we packed up everything we owned and now have a new start in a
a new townhouse.</p>

<p>I sit here, surrounded by boxes and bare walls, having already spent an
untold number of days putting every one of my worldly possessions into boxes
just to remove them upon arrival at this new house, and knowing I&#8217;ll spend many
more before reaching the end.</p>

<p>Things are good and I am overall quite happy, but if someone told me, &#8220;you will
have to stop all work on anything productive for the next 2 months while you
do nothing but pick your stuff up here and put it away on the other side&#8221; I&#8217;d
have told them to shove something somewhere where things aren&#8217;t meant to shoved.</p>

<p>Instead of being a lot further along building <a href="http://scalesapp.com">Scales</a> I
have moved my stuff from over there to over here. &lt;sarcasm>Awesome.
&lt;\/sarcasm></p>

<p>The first few days here were exciting:
* Look at all the organizing I can do!
* Everything can be put in its rightful place
* Clean all the things!
* There are so many possibilities</p>

<p>But now that the honeymoon period has worn off, I&#8217;m left with a ton of boxes and
little motivation. I&#8217;ve put away and dealt with the fun things, all that&#8217;s left
is the tedious boring stuff. I&#8217;ll slog through it and my wife will no doubt help
keep me motivated but man is it a drag.</p>

<p>I. Hate. Moving.</p>
]]><a href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2013/01/06/moving/"><strong>∮</strong></a><br /><br /></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cloud9]]></title>
    <link href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/12/23/cloud9/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-23T15:19:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/12/23/cloud9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://victorquinn.com/images/cloud9.png"></p>

<p>I have been following the <a href="http://c9.io">Cloud9</a> project since its early
days. I was thrilled at their open source editor, Ace (formerly Bespin) and
actually wrote a <a href="http://drupal.org/node/1377948">Drupal WYSIWYG plugin</a> to
allow it as an option for HTML editing in Drupal.</p>

<p>But, when I originally looked at Cloud9, as neat as it was to be able to edit
files in the cloud, it wasn&#8217;t really too useful for much.</p>

<p>Just recently a co-worker sent me a link to some code he had written using it
with some client-side javascript code. It was nothing short of magical.</p>

<p>This. Changes. Everything.</p>

<p>Wondering what it&#8217;ll be like to develop in the future? Just try out Cloud9.</p>

<h2>Direct git Integration</h2>

<p>Cloud9 can pair with your <a href="http://github.com">Github</a> or
<a href="http://bitbucket.com">Bitbucket</a> account and pull in all the code in any of your
repositories. So with just the click of a button you&#8217;re up and running with your
code. That&#8217;s pretty awesome.</p>

<p>But they actually had this awhile back when I tried it (though it now is even
more fluid and awesome). What has changed?</p>

<h2>The old problem</h2>

<p>Code editing in the cloud was neat and all, but I had to commit any changes I
made so I could check them out locally or on my webserver so I could test it and
see if it blew everything up or fixed the problem I was trying to solve.</p>

<p>This led to a tortured workflow involving committing sometimes not working code
in Cloud9, checking it out locally, running it, seeing if it worked or broke,
editing and bugfixing it locally, committing that, then going back to work in
Cloud9. As I&#8217;m sure you can imagine, Cloud9 quickly dropped out of my workflow
and I went back to just editing everything locally.</p>

<h2>The solution arrives!</h2>

<p>Imagine my surprise and wonder upon most recently checking out Cloud9 when it
had the ability to run code, in your browser! It can easily handle node.js,
rails, I&#8217;m sure more. It even handled this Jekyll-based blog with ease! In fact
I am editing this now, in Cloud9!</p>

<p>It has GUI shortcuts for things like git commands, npm install/uninstall, and
more, but it also allows you to drop directly into a terminal and run commands
there! It&#8217;s just like having your own server with none of the headache.</p>

<h2>Always in sync across systems</h2>

<p>One of my favorite benefits of this approach is that everything is, by its
nature always in sync across systems. I can pick up my laptop, do some work,
then move to my desktop, open Cloud9 and everything is just as I left it. I
could go sit down in a random computer lab or library and still be in sync and
ready to roll.</p>

<p>This last bit, in my opinion, is the most powerful feature of this kind
of Cloud programming. For $0, I can have an always in sync IDE operable from any
browser, my own cloud server, and more. It took awhile for the gravity of this
to sink in, but this is pretty amazing. The barrier to entry for programming
with a server has never been lower</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>There&#8217;s a lot more to discuss that I&#8217;m not touching on here, just wanted to hit
some of the quick highlights. I&#8217;m trying to work this into my workflow more so
I&#8217;m sure I&#8217;ll have more thoughts later.</p>

<p>This is seriously awesome and feels like the future&#8230;</p>
]]><a href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/12/23/cloud9/"><strong>∮</strong></a><br /><br /></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing Scales]]></title>
    <link href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/11/25/launching-scales/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-25T18:31:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/11/25/launching-scales</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I officially announce the initial launch of the new website for my startup called <a href="http://scalesapp.com">Scales</a>.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://victorquinn.com/images/scales-icon.png" width="256" height="256"></p>

<p>Named for the implement held in one hand by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lady_Justice">Lady Justice</a>, Scales will focus on creating innovative learning solutions for law students.</p>

<p>More info is available on the <a href="http://scalesapp.com">Scales</a> site, but in brief my goal is to meld my knowledge of the law with my skills as a software architect and build something unlike anything else that currently exists. Scales will offer a fresh new take on legal supplements, bringing them into the 21st century.</p>

<p>For the tech nerds out there, Scales is a <a href="http://rubyonrails.org">Ruby on Rails</a> application which will serve as the central repository for info, study materials, quiz questions, and other learning content. I will then build out a web experience directly in Rails using <a href="http://backbonejs.org">Backbone.js</a> to ensure it&#8217;s snappy along with an iOS app which will communicate to that main web app via an API. Content and progress created in the Rails app will by seamlessly synchronized to the iOS app and vice versa with some intelligent caching so lack of connectivity will never be blocking.</p>

<p>With my rich background in software development building APIs, my plan is to be able to offer a top notch, fully integrated experience for legal education unlike any other currently out there which is also open for future expansion to Android devices or desktop applications or whatever else the future may have in store. (Direct mindlink anybody?)</p>

<p>I am flying solo on this project so progress may seem somewhat slow at the start, but will always be steady and I hope to have a true initial launch with content for a core set of courses sometime in Spring 2013. Please stay tuned for updates and if you are interested please do not hesitate to <a href="mailto:mail@victorquinn.com?subject=Scales">contact me</a>.</p>

<p>In the meantime any posts relating to Scales will be tagged appropriately and can all be viewed <a href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/categories/scales/">on this page</a>.</p>
]]><a href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/11/25/launching-scales/"><strong>∮</strong></a><br /><br /></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fresh look]]></title>
    <link href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/11/01/fresh-look/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-01T00:27:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/11/01/fresh-look</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Decided it was time for a fresh new look.</p>

<p>For reference, a screenshot of the old design:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://victorquinn.com/images/oldstyle.png"></p>

<p>I wanted to redesign to make it cleaner and simpler, to better highlight the content, and to move to something which felt a bit less constrained with some more fun colors. I had grown bored of the green everywhere. I&#8217;m quite pleased with the outcome.</p>
]]><a href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/11/01/fresh-look/"><strong>∮</strong></a><br /><br /></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Civic Drupal Module]]></title>
    <link href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/10/26/google-civic-drupal-module/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-26T16:28:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/10/26/google-civic-drupal-module</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the nice things about working for a political company is the ability to work in a fast-moving field, especially close to election time.</p>

<p>Just a few weeks ago Google came out with a new API called <a href="https://developers.google.com/civic-information/">Civic</a> which allows you to pass in an address and get back a bunch of information related to voting in the upcoming election. It will return things such as polling places, candidates, and other election information.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://victorquinn.com/images/google.png"></p>

<p>Our company took this to task and created a Drupal module which interacts with this new API service so people can easily add a &#8220;Find my polling place&#8221; widget to their Drupal website. This should hopefully get more people informed about the election and getting out to vote.</p>

<p>For my part, I took the Drupal 6 version created by my co-workers and ported it to Drupal 7. I also added (Drupal 7 only for now) some other cool info based on your address such as information on the relevant contests and links to the candidate pages so voters can be well informed going into election day.</p>

<p>Check it out!</p>

<p><a href="http://d7demo.ngpvanhost.com">Try out a demo</a></p>

<p><a href="http://drupal.org/project/google_civic">Module page on drupal.org</a></p>
]]><a href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/10/26/google-civic-drupal-module/"><strong>∮</strong></a><br /><br /></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[git commit partial]]></title>
    <link href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/10/18/git-commit-partial/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-18T10:38:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/10/18/git-commit-partial</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of my favorite git tricks is the ability to commit only part of a file. This is a short but sweet tip.</p>

<p>Just use:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>git add -p filename.rb
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>This will ask you whether or not to stage each hunk of the file so you can commit that awesome change you made at the top, not stage the middle piece which is still a work in progress, and stage the piece at the bottom your team member needs to keep making progress.</p>
]]><a href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/10/18/git-commit-partial/"><strong>∮</strong></a><br /><br /></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[cd which directory]]></title>
    <link href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/10/15/cd-which-directory/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-15T10:04:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/10/15/cd-which-directory</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sharing a minor tweak which has been very useful to me.</p>

<p>I find I often want to cd into the directory where a program exists. Let&#8217;s say I was trying to jump to the directory which contained <em>myawesomeprogram</em> but didn&#8217;t know where it was. My old workflow was something like:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>which myawesomeprogram
</span><span class='line'><span class="c"># Manually click/drag to copy and paste the resulting output</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nb">cd</span> &lt;pasted directory&gt;
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Come on, I&#8217;m an übernerd, surely I can figure out something better/more efficient which doesn&#8217;t require me to touch my mouse.</p>

<h2>Enter a simple zsh function</h2>

<p>I use <a href="http://zsh.sourceforge.net">zsh</a> for my shell. I think this should work with bash though YMMV.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>cdw <span class="o">()</span> <span class="o">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nb">cd</span> <span class="k">$(</span>dirname <span class="k">$(</span>which <span class="nv">$1</span><span class="k">))</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="o">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Adding this to my .zshrc allows me to just type</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>cdw myawesomeprogram
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>and I&#8217;m immediately teleported to the folder which contains that program.</p>
]]><a href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/10/15/cd-which-directory/"><strong>∮</strong></a><br /><br /></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Capybara and RSpec to test Drupal]]></title>
    <link href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/10/11/using-capybara-and-rspec-to-test-drupal/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-11T14:49:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/10/11/using-capybara-and-rspec-to-test-drupal</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>tl;dr</h2>

<p>I created a git repo with a framework for testing Drupal sites using Capybara webkit and RSpec so any Drupal developers can just clone it and go.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/victorquinn/drupal-capybara">View project on Github</a></p>

<h2>Rationale</h2>

<p>The first question I&#8217;m likely to get here is &#8220;Why?&#8221; Drupal has its own testing framework <a href="http://drupal.org/simpletest">SimpleTest</a> which can be used for both Unit and Functional tests, so why try to use RSpec/Ruby? Also, SimpleTest has access to all of the Drupal-y goodness, why write functional tests in Ruby where those functions would not be available?</p>

<p>That&#8217;s a great question. In my case I&#8217;m trying to run tests on a Drupal instance that is on a different machine. In my case I&#8217;m trying to run the tests from by desktop and hit my production web server which is on an offsite clustered server. Here SimpleTest wouldn&#8217;t fit the bill. These tests allow me to take into account network latency and such.</p>

<p>Note, of course since these tests are not in Drupal, tests written and performed like this will not do the setup/teardown like SimpleTest. So I would strongly suggest only touching data on test websites.</p>

<h2>Setup</h2>

<p>First, test that ruby exists and is the right version.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>ruby -v
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>I used ruby 1.9.3-p194 managed by <a href="https://rvm.io">rvm</a> but I believe any 1.9+ version of ruby should work here with Capybara.</p>

<p>Next, clone my repo which is basically a skeleton setup ready to test Drupal using Capybara. In the repo I&#8217;ve included a file called default.config.yaml. You will want to copy that file to config.yaml. The Gemfile should be set up to install all necessary dependencies.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>git clone git://github.com/victorquinn/drupal-capybara.git
</span><span class='line'>cp default.config.yaml config.yaml
</span><span class='line'>bundle install
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Now edit config.yaml and change the values to match the Drupal site you are testing.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='yaml'><span class='line'><span class="l-Scalar-Plain">site</span><span class="p-Indicator">:</span> <span class="s">&quot;http://mycoolwebsite.com&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="l-Scalar-Plain">user</span><span class="p-Indicator">:</span> <span class="l-Scalar-Plain">myusername</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="l-Scalar-Plain">password</span><span class="p-Indicator">:</span> <span class="l-Scalar-Plain">abcd1234</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<h2>Is it working?</h2>

<p>I&#8217;ve included two sample tests, one which will just check to ensure the site can be hit and the second which should try logging in to your Drupal site using the values in config.yaml. I&#8217;ve tested this both on Drupal 6 and Drupal 7 and works out of the box on both.</p>

<p>Try to run the tests and ensure things work. Go to the root of that directory (drupal-capybara by default) and try to run it! (do not try to run this from inside the spec directory, you&#8217;ll get errors.)</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>rspec spec
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>You should see something like the following:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>2012-10-12 11:45:18.027 webkit_server<span class="o">[</span>73469:707<span class="o">]</span> *** WARNING: Method userSpaceScaleFactor in class NSView is deprecated on 10.7 and later. It should not be used in new applications. Use convertRectToBacking: instead.
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>..
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>Finished in 4.23 seconds
</span><span class='line'>2 examples, 0 failures
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>The warnings can be safely ignored. I am not sure exactly why they&#8217;re there, something to do with the way the Capybara webkit code is with Mountain Lion. But it&#8217;s just a warning and doesn&#8217;t have anything to do with our web tests.</p>

<p>Note: The login test I included will only work if your system has not altered the login page. If something has changed the Log In button to say &#8220;Login&#8221; or &#8220;Go&#8221; or &#8220;Submit&#8221; or anything else, the test will fail. This is one of the downsides of trying to write tests for Drupal in a system that is not associated with Drupal &#8211; it cannot dynamically know about anything which has changed internal to Drupal.</p>

<p>** Capybara webkit can be a bit of a tricky beast to get installed on your system with dependencies and such. <a href="#troubleshooting_webkit">Jump to the bottom</a> to see more details on some possible solutions.</p>

<p>Now test that tests fail correctly by changing your password in config.yaml to a bad value and run it again.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='yaml'><span class='line'><span class="l-Scalar-Plain">site</span><span class="p-Indicator">:</span> <span class="s">&quot;http://mycoolwebsite.com&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="l-Scalar-Plain">user</span><span class="p-Indicator">:</span> <span class="l-Scalar-Plain">myusername</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="l-Scalar-Plain">password</span><span class="p-Indicator">:</span> <span class="l-Scalar-Plain">notmypassword</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>You should see something like the following:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>2012-10-12 11:42:51.760 webkit_server<span class="o">[</span>72603:707<span class="o">]</span> *** WARNING: Method userSpaceScaleFactor in class NSView is deprecated on 10.7 and later. It should not be used in new applications. Use convertRectToBacking: instead.
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>Failures:
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  1<span class="o">)</span> DrupalTest login works
</span><span class='line'>     Failure/Error: verify_login_worked
</span><span class='line'>       expected <span class="c">#has_content?(&quot;Sorry, unrecognized username or password.&quot;) to return false, got true</span>
</span><span class='line'>     <span class="c"># ./spec/drupal_test_helper.rb:10:in `verify_login_worked&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>     <span class="c"># ./spec/drupal_capybara_spec.rb:27:in `block (2 levels) in &lt;top (required)&gt;&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>Finished in 3.46 seconds
</span><span class='line'>2 examples, 1 failure
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>Failed examples:
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>rspec ./spec/drupal_capybara_spec.rb:25 <span class="c"># DrupalTest login works</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Here failure is a good thing! Shouldn&#8217;t be able to log in if the password is wrong. Don&#8217;t forget to change your password back in config.yaml before moving on.</p>

<p>This isn&#8217;t a full rspec tutorial as such, but with my example tests that should be a good start. I&#8217;ve included a third sample test of filling out a Drupal form in my code (specifically in <em>spec/drupal_capybara_spec.rb</em>, but it&#8217;s commented out by default because that&#8217;s kind of specific to the particulars of the site and I didn&#8217;t want to send this out with tests likely to fail on most systems.</p>

<p>I should note, you can also run RSpec to get a nice HTML output. Just run the following:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>rspec spec --format html --out results.html
</span><span class='line'><span class="c"># And if you&#39;re on a Mac, to open the results in a browser, just run:</span>
</span><span class='line'>open results.html
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p><em>You should be all set and ready to write some tests!</em></p>

<h2><a id="troubleshooting_webkit"></a>Troubleshooting Capybara Webkit</h2>

<p>Not to sugar coat things, I found Capybara Webkit pretty painful to get installed.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ll help with the issues I overcame, but generally it will likely involve some googling and such as it&#8217;s very dependent on the particulars of the system on which this is being run. For reference, I am on Mountain Lion (10.8.2) using ruby 1.9.3-p194. I also use <a href="http://mxcl.github.com/homebrew/">HomeBrew</a> to manage packages.</p>

<p>If you get the following error:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>Installing capybara-webkit <span class="o">(</span>0.12.1<span class="o">)</span> with native extensions
</span><span class='line'>Gem::Installer::ExtensionBuildError: ERROR: Failed to build gem native extension.
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>        /Users/&lt;username&gt;/.rvm/rubies/ruby-1.9.3-p194/bin/ruby extconf.rb
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>Gem files will remain installed in /Users/&lt;username&gt;/.rvm/gems/ruby-1.9.3-p194/gems/capybara-webkit-0.12.1 <span class="k">for </span>inspection.
</span><span class='line'>Results logged to /Users/&lt;username&gt;/.rvm/gems/ruby-1.9.3-p194/gems/capybara-webkit-0.12.1/./gem_make.out
</span><span class='line'>An error occured <span class="k">while </span>installing capybara-webkit <span class="o">(</span>0.12.1<span class="o">)</span>, and Bundler cannot <span class="k">continue</span>.
</span><span class='line'>Make sure that <span class="sb">`</span>gem install capybara-webkit -v <span class="s1">&#39;0.12.1&#39;</span><span class="sb">`</span> succeeds before bundling.
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Then it&#8217;s likely qt is not installed on your system. I resolved this by running:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>brew install qt libpng
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Mentioned above, but if you&#8217;re on Mountain Lion you will likely see a warning such as:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>2012-10-11 18:16:42.457 webkit_server<span class="o">[</span>64967:707<span class="o">]</span> *** WARNING: Method userSpaceScaleFactor in class NSView is deprecated on 10.7 and later. It should not be used in new applications. Use convertRectToBacking: instead.
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>but it can safely be ignored.</p>

<p>If all else fails and you cannot get Webkit working on your system, Selenium can be used instead of Capybara Webkit so all this magic still works, just using Selenium instead of Webkit.</p>

<h3>Alternative setup with Selenium</h3>

<p>To use Selenium instead of headless Webkit, simply edit the drupal_capybara_spec.rb file as follows:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'><span class="c1"># Before</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="no">Capybara</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">default_driver</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="ss">:webkit</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="no">Capybara</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">javascript_driver</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="ss">:webkit</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c1"># After</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="no">Capybara</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">default_driver</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="ss">:selenium</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>

]]><a href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/10/11/using-capybara-and-rspec-to-test-drupal/"><strong>∮</strong></a><br /><br /></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Naming Agile Sprints]]></title>
    <link href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/10/08/naming-agile-sprints/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-08T21:32:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/10/08/naming-agile-sprints</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a trivial post of sorts.</p>

<p>There are 52 weeks in the year. My company follows 2 week sprints for development using an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Agile_software_development">Agile Development</a> process called <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scrum_(development">Scrum</a>).</p>

<p>52 divided by 2 yields 26.</p>

<p>How many letters are in the alphabet? Oh right, 26.</p>

<p>So using the letters A-Z it is possible to represent each sprint uniquely by just a letter of the alphabet just like hurricanes or Ubuntu.</p>

<p>So let&#8217;s make sprint planning, a generally dry and boring affair, interesting.</p>

<p>Since I began leading sprints in my role as team lead with my current employer, my team has planned each sprint using a letter of the alphabet. But not just a letter of the alphabet, we&#8217;ve used the first letter to represent some adjective and the second to represent a mythical god.</p>

<p>We have had such gems as Entropic <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Echo_(mythology)">Echo</a>, Fab <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fortuna">Fortuna</a>, Hapless <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lernaean_Hydra">Hydra</a>, Gravid <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Godhead">Godhead</a>, and we are currently nearing the end of Jovial <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jah">Jah</a>.</p>

<p>I am hardly the first one to think of this, but it has done us well and adds some much needed jazz to an otherwise boring affair.</p>

<p>In the midst of one of the most tiresome aspects of development, the sprint planning, we begin a debate on which adjective/mythical being pair would best represent our current sprint. Excellent and enjoyable arguments ensue as each person argues that their adjective/god pair most closely resembles the sprint we have just planned. The monotony has been cut with an amusing nonsensical argument about how Entropic this sprint is or the etymology of God vs. Godhead vs. Gaia. What does it mean to be a God? Amusement rises from a once dry conversation as an excited debate ignites. Developers who were once dreary of the seemingly endless task of planning the coming weeks spring to life in an attempt to argue that their pairing of adjective and god is most apt.</p>

<p>And I&#8217;ve done so against resistance. I have been told that company policy forbade such a tactic, that tradition was to name the sprint by the (boring) start and end date and to diverge was verboten. I now technically name sprints by the start and end date, but tack on my team consensus amusing god name as a suffix. Since &#8220;Ardent Atlas&#8221; was forbidden, we now have &#8220;May 22 - June 5, Bashful Baal&#8221; to appease the powers that be while maintaining autonomy and team spirit.</p>

<p>The thing I love most about this is that there is no trickery here. This is not like the spoon zoomed toward the infant like it&#8217;s an airplane while the spoon holder mockingly looks down upon the infant as, well, infantile. Rather this is just a moment to enjoy the company of other intellectuals and have a respectful debate about something downright silly and frankly nonsensical to mix things up. It is an excuse to forget about the nitty gritty details of the boring nature of what had just been planned and just wax philosophically and passionately about definitions and minutiae in a manner which few other sectors af the human race would appreciate as much as developers happen to.</p>

<p>Keeping developers happy is arguably the greatest challenge in the management of software engineers and this little trivial tidbit has added some nice spice to an otherwise boring dish.</p>
]]><a href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/10/08/naming-agile-sprints/"><strong>∮</strong></a><br /><br /></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Homebrew Tip #45]]></title>
    <link href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/10/07/homebrew-tip-number-45/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-07T12:53:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/10/07/homebrew-tip-number-45</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Warm malt extract during brewing so less is wasted.</h2>

<p>When I start the homebrew process, the first step of which is sanitizing all my equipment, I first plug one of my sinks, put my liquid malt extract into it (still in its containers), then fill it with hot water.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://victorquinn.com/images/lme1.png"></p>

<p>I pick up the liquid malt extract container from time to time and give it a shake to evenly distribute it throughout the container. I also periodically drain and refresh the hot water it&#8217;s bathed in to keep it hot as the malt extract absorbs the heat. This also melts the glue so the labels can be pulled off easily. You&#8217;ll see in my image above that one has its label all the way off and the other is starting to peel. Removing this makes doubly sure that nothing falls into the wort.</p>

<p>By doing this, it makes the malt extract much more viscous (read: runny) so when it comes time to add it to the wort, less is wasted because more of it runs out while pouring and less sticks to the inside of the container.</p>

<p>Bonus: If using a plastic container with a lid (for example with <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000V5XAQK/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B000V5XAQK&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=victorqcom-20" title="">Briess Liquid Malt Extract</a>) you can do as above, but also, after pouring out the malt extract, you can fill this plastic container with hot water from the tap, shake it around, and pour it into the wort. This will ensure even more of your malt extract makes its way into the wort and little is wasted. This can also be done with an aluminum can but it will be less efficient.</p>
]]><a href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/10/07/homebrew-tip-number-45/"><strong>∮</strong></a><br /><br /></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Programmatically Creating Fielded Nodes in Drupal 7]]></title>
    <link href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/08/11/programmatically-creating-fielded-d7-nodes/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-11T18:23:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/08/11/programmatically-creating-fielded-d7-nodes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>The Setup</h3>

<p>You&#8217;ve just created your new super awesome node type in Drupal 7 using the (now in core!) Content type editor.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://victorquinn.com/images/contenttype1.png"></p>

<p>Now you want to programmatically generate some Super Awesome Content nodes. Some <a href="https://www.google.com">Googling</a> (or <a href="https://duckduckgo.com">Ducking</a>!) will land you with some snippets that look as follows:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span>Works with standard node  </span></figcaption>
 <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='php'><span class='line'><span class="cp">&lt;?php</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">function</span> <span class="nf">create_my_node</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nv">$node</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="k">new</span> <span class="k">stdClass</span><span class="p">();</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nv">$node</span><span class="o">-&gt;</span><span class="na">type</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s1">&#39;blog&#39;</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">node_object_prepare</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nv">$node</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nv">$node</span><span class="o">-&gt;</span><span class="na">title</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s2">&quot;My Awesome Title&quot;</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nv">$node</span><span class="o">-&gt;</span><span class="na">language</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">LANGUAGE_NONE</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">node_save</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nv">$node</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<h3>The Problem</h3>

<p>Since you&#8217;ve defined a custom content type, you may think something like the following would work great with your new custom node type to set your custom field values:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span>Attempt with custom node (this will fail!)  </span></figcaption>
 <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='php'><span class='line'><span class="cp">&lt;?php</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">function</span> <span class="nf">create_my_node</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nv">$node</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="k">new</span> <span class="k">stdClass</span><span class="p">();</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nv">$node</span><span class="o">-&gt;</span><span class="na">type</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s1">&#39;super_awesome_content&#39;</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">node_object_prepare</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nv">$node</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nv">$node</span><span class="o">-&gt;</span><span class="na">title</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s2">&quot;My Awesome Title&quot;</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nv">$node</span><span class="o">-&gt;</span><span class="na">language</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">LANGUAGE_NONE</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="c1">// Try to set your custom field values</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nv">$node</span><span class="o">-&gt;</span><span class="na">field_reasons_for_being_awesome</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s2">&quot;Too many to count...&quot;</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nv">$node</span><span class="o">-&gt;</span><span class="na">field_awesome_points</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="mi">23</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">node_save</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nv">$node</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>However, that will fail! Why? Because you can&#8217;t set node custom fields like you may expect with <em>$node->{$key}</em>.</p>

<p><em>In my opinion, this is one thing Drupal 7 got very wrong. I&#8217;ll explain their rationale in a bit after showing the correct way to do this and it does make some sense, but it seems unnecessarily complicated.</em></p>

<h3>The Solution</h3>

<p>Instead of trying to set those custom field attributes directly, you have to use the following funky syntax:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span>Successful attempt with custom node (this totally works!)  </span></figcaption>
 <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='php'><span class='line'><span class="cp">&lt;?php</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">function</span> <span class="nf">create_my_node</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nv">$node</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="k">new</span> <span class="k">stdClass</span><span class="p">();</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nv">$node</span><span class="o">-&gt;</span><span class="na">type</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s1">&#39;super_awesome_content&#39;</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">node_object_prepare</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nv">$node</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nv">$node</span><span class="o">-&gt;</span><span class="na">title</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s2">&quot;My Awesome Title&quot;</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nv">$node</span><span class="o">-&gt;</span><span class="na">language</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">LANGUAGE_NONE</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="c1">// Try to set your custom field</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nv">$node</span><span class="o">-&gt;</span><span class="na">field_reasons_for_being_awesome</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="s1">&#39;und&#39;</span><span class="p">][</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">][</span><span class="s1">&#39;value&#39;</span><span class="p">]</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s2">&quot;Too many to count...&quot;</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nv">$node</span><span class="o">-&gt;</span><span class="na">field_awesome_points</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="s1">&#39;und&#39;</span><span class="p">][</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">][</span><span class="s1">&#39;value&#39;</span><span class="p">]</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="mi">23</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">node_save</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nv">$node</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Huh? What&#8217;s with this <em>[&#8216;und&#8217;][0][&#8216;value&#8217;]</em> stuff?</p>

<p>Well, it&#8217;s a bit complicated. Let&#8217;s break it down piece by piece</p>

<h4>[&#8216;und&#8217;]</h4>

<p>This first bit is the language to be applied to the field. <em>&#8216;und&#8217;</em> is the key specifying that the language is undefined. This could also be &#8216;en&#8217; or &#8216;de&#8217; or &#8216;fr&#8217; or any other 2 letter language code if a particular language is specified for this field.</p>

<h4>[0]</h4>

<p>This is an array index. For any single value fields like the ones we have, this is just [0]. But it&#8217;s conceivable to have multiple values in which this would kind of make sense. For example, let&#8217;s say our reasons_for_being_awesome field was a multi-value field:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span>Multi-value field  </span></figcaption>
 <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='php'><span class='line'><span class="cp">&lt;?php</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="o">...</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nv">$node</span><span class="o">-&gt;</span><span class="na">field_reasons_for_being_awesome</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="s1">&#39;und&#39;</span><span class="p">][</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">][</span><span class="s1">&#39;value&#39;</span><span class="p">]</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s2">&quot;Too many to count...&quot;</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nv">$node</span><span class="o">-&gt;</span><span class="na">field_reasons_for_being_awesome</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="s1">&#39;und&#39;</span><span class="p">][</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">][</span><span class="s1">&#39;value&#39;</span><span class="p">]</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s2">&quot;Reason number 2&quot;</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nv">$node</span><span class="o">-&gt;</span><span class="na">field_reasons_for_being_awesome</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="s1">&#39;und&#39;</span><span class="p">][</span><span class="mi">2</span><span class="p">][</span><span class="s1">&#39;value&#39;</span><span class="p">]</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s2">&quot;Another reason&quot;</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nv">$node</span><span class="o">-&gt;</span><span class="na">field_reasons_for_being_awesome</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="s1">&#39;und&#39;</span><span class="p">][</span><span class="mi">3</span><span class="p">][</span><span class="s1">&#39;value&#39;</span><span class="p">]</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s2">&quot;The most important reason&quot;</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">node_save</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nv">$node</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>So it makes some sense for the array index to be there, but it&#8217;s somewhat confusing for what is arguably the main use case &#8211; namely trying to assign a single value to a field.</p>

<h4>[&#8216;value&#8217;]</h4>

<p>This may be the oddest piece. There are a few other keys which could be specified here, among them <em>[&#8216;format&#8217;]</em> and <em>[&#8216;summary&#8217;]</em>, but when working programmatically with custom fields, it&#8217;s rare to be setting anything other than <em>[&#8216;value&#8217;]</em>.</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span>Summary  </span></figcaption>
 <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='php'><span class='line'><span class="cp">&lt;?php</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="c1">// Won&#39;t work</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nv">$node</span><span class="o">-&gt;</span><span class="na">field_reasons_for_being_awesome</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s2">&quot;Too many to count...&quot;</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nv">$node</span><span class="o">-&gt;</span><span class="na">field_awesome_points</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="mi">23</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="c1">// Will work</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nv">$node</span><span class="o">-&gt;</span><span class="na">field_reasons_for_being_awesome</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="s1">&#39;und&#39;</span><span class="p">][</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">][</span><span class="s1">&#39;value&#39;</span><span class="p">]</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s2">&quot;Too many to count...&quot;</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nv">$node</span><span class="o">-&gt;</span><span class="na">field_awesome_points</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="s1">&#39;und&#39;</span><span class="p">][</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">][</span><span class="s1">&#39;value&#39;</span><span class="p">]</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="mi">23</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<h3>Commentary</h3>

<p>I think Drupal should be much better here and dropped the ball for developers by not allowing the first method above to work. This [&#8216;und&#8217;][0][&#8216;value&#8217;] mess may make it easier for the system to deal with the input, but it makes things far more difficult/complicated for developers. This is an area where it&#8217;s painfully clear that the Drupal Field API is not a true ORM like <a href="http://api.rubyonrails.org/classes/ActiveRecord/Base.html">ActiveRecord</a> and in my opinion that&#8217;s a missed opportunity.</p>

<p>Ideally the system would be able to default to allowing things to be set with just the key and not require developers to specify the language, array index, and value key every single time a value is set to the field.</p>
]]><a href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/08/11/programmatically-creating-fielded-d7-nodes/"><strong>∮</strong></a><br /><br /></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My New Motorcycle!]]></title>
    <link href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/04/22/my-new-motorcycle/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-22T19:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/04/22/my-new-motorcycle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Went out yesterday and bought myself a new toy.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://victorquinn.com/images/motorcycle.jpg"></p>

<p>It&#8217;s a <a href="http://www.harley-davidson.com/en_US/Motorcycles/1200-custom.html">2012 Harley Davidson Sportster 1200 Custom</a></p>

<p>I have more pics on <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/victorquinn/sets/72157629504793470/">flickr</a>.</p>
]]><a href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/04/22/my-new-motorcycle/"><strong>∮</strong></a><br /><br /></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RubyNation 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/03/22/rubynation-2012/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-22T23:05:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/03/22/rubynation-2012</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ll be at RubyNation 2012 tomorrow.</p>

<p>Getting my laptop set up and ready to roll so I&#8217;ll be ready to code like a madman.</p>

<p>I love <a href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/03/15/attending-rubynation-2012/">conferences</a> ;)</p>

<p>If you&#8217;ll be there, find me or <a href="https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?screen_name=victorquinn" class="twitter-mention-button" data-lang="en">Tweet to @victorquinn</a></p>

<script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0];if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js";fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document,"script","twitter-wjs");</script>

]]><a href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/03/22/rubynation-2012/"><strong>∮</strong></a><br /><br /></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Solved: git svn broken in Mountain Lion DP2]]></title>
    <link href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/03/20/solved-git-svn-broken-in-mountain-lion-dp2/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-20T22:08:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/03/20/solved-git-svn-broken-in-mountain-lion-dp2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over this past weekend, I installed Mountain Lion Developer Preview 2 (DP2).</p>

<p>It came with another version of Xcode and I was heartbroken to once again see that git svn was broken!</p>

<p>However, I was relieved to find that my <a href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/02/19/fix-git-svn-in-mountain-lion/">previous solution</a> worked like a charm. I was able to copy-paste the exact commands again and everything worked perfectly.</p>

<p>I updated the former post accordingly and it&#8217;s available <a href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/02/19/fix-git-svn-in-mountain-lion/">here</a></p>
]]><a href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/03/20/solved-git-svn-broken-in-mountain-lion-dp2/"><strong>∮</strong></a><br /><br /></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stripe Ubercart Module for Drupal]]></title>
    <link href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/03/16/stripe-ubercart-module-for-drupal/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-16T16:46:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/03/16/stripe-ubercart-module-for-drupal</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back in October of last year, I wrote an Ubercart plugin for Stripe <sup><a href="#stripe1">[1]</a></sup>, a payment API created to be developer conscious and easy to use. I loved the idea of Stripe <sup><a href="#stripe2">[2]</a></sup> and was using Ubercart for a project and noticed there was no module so I created it.</p>

<p>It was the first contrib module I had created entirely from scratch on my own which made it through the Drupal.org submission process. I&#8217;ve written many custom modules for my employer and for side projects, but this was my first time going through the gauntlet of the review process for getting a contrib module on Drupal.org. For the curious, you can see the whole back and forth on this issue: <a href="http://drupal.org/node/1339850">http://drupal.org/node/1339850</a></p>

<p>I recently noticed Stripe links back to my module from their site.<sup><a href="#stripe3">[3]</a></sup></p>

<p><a id="stripe1"></a>[1] <a href="http://drupal.org/project/uc_stripe">Ubercart plugin for Stripe</a>
<a id="stripe2"></a>[2] <a href="https://stripe.com">Stripe</a>
<a id="stripe3"></a>[3] <a href="site.https://stripe.com/docs/libraries#third-party">Stripe link to my Ubercart Stripe Module</a></p>
]]><a href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/03/16/stripe-ubercart-module-for-drupal/"><strong>∮</strong></a><br /><br /></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Developer Conference Excitement]]></title>
    <link href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/03/15/attending-rubynation-2012/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-15T10:36:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/03/15/attending-rubynation-2012</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Excited to attend the <a href="http://www.rubynation.org/">RubyNation</a> 2012 conference next week!</p>

<p>This will be the first year since 2009 that I will not be attending <a href="http://denver2012.drupal.org/">DrupalCon</a> <sup><a href="#excitement1">[1]</a></sup> and my conference itch needs scratching.</p>

<p>I find generally that conference excitement manifests itself in a handful of ways.</p>

<h2>New Things!</h2>

<p>My favorite thing about attending a programming conference is the excitement I have during and immediately after for all the new things I will learn at the conference.</p>

<p>Every time I walk out of a room where someone was giving a presentation on a cool new technology or process, in the back of my head I am thinking of how I can work that technology or process into each of my current projects. Or I am pondering what old projects I could revamp or new projects I could start using this technology as a launchpad which were previously out of scope or cost prohibitive.</p>

<p>Setting aside the new things themselves, this type of self-reflection and evaluation is invaluable. I strive for this type of reflection in my everyday life, but it&#8217;s much easier in this type of forum, removed from the daily doldrums of life at the office. Having traveled to a conference, often far away, and broken the routine, it is easier to have this kind of perspective.</p>

<p>New things also inherently bring excitement for their new-ness, particularly for a person like myself. Some people enjoy consistency and sameness and have an aversion to change. I am the exact opposite and view a new thing as a new challenge ready and ripe for besting. It also represents uncharted territory and I am definitely an explorer.</p>

<h2>High Energy Environment</h2>

<p>There is always an extremely high energy level at such conferences.</p>

<p>The speakers have high energy, speaking excitedly about something interesting they have recently worked on in an attempt to proselytize.</p>

<p>This in turn leads me (and others) to similarly get excited about their new thing. This kind of network effect is huge. When high energy people start bouncing ideas off of each other in a sort of feedback loop, great things can result.</p>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='Never weary of the cost to implement, I am a constant proponent for whatever will be objectively best.'>
I had a reputation with my co-workers of being the guy with the kooky fringe ideas. This is because I was always excited about the possibility of using new and more efficient concepts in our projects. For someone like me, a conference was like crack. Never weary of the cost to implement, I am a constant proponent for whatever will be objectively best. It always led to interesting meals during conferences with me excitedly ranting about how we could use X for this project or Y for that project with my co-workers offering counterpoints to keep me grounded. I&#8217;m sure they grew weary at times, but my co-workers generally allowed me to indulge.
</span></p>

<p>My first week back after a conference is always absorbed by planning and trying to implement many of the new things I learned at the conference or figuring out a reason why I couldn&#8217;t or shouldn&#8217;t. I feel like I&#8217;m kicked into high gear, being three times as productive that week as any other while I run on the natural high from learning about new things as most people run on coffee.</p>

<p><span class='pullquote-left' data-pullquote='My employer benefited greatly as a result, but that was not my intent in working like mad.'>
I notice myself staying voluntarily late at work and working much longer hours than normal or necessary which, for a salaried employee, was solely for my own personal enjoyment. My employer benefited greatly as a result, but that was not my intent in working like mad. I was rushing to solve a new puzzle, to conquer a new opponent. I was working purely for enjoyment.
</span></p>

<p>Another high energy aspect is that each of the attendees is there to learn. Almost like a wedding, where another new beginning is celebrated, most attendees are embarking on a journey of their own with a technology. Most attendees get a break from their normal day at the office and this fills them with energy and joy they wouldn&#8217;t otherwise have.</p>

<p>Being around people in a natural state of high energy serves to amplify the learning and the network effects of the conference.</p>

<h2>Networking</h2>

<p>And of course there is the value of networking. Many people go to developer conferences primarily for this aspect.</p>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='It is nearly priceless to compare notes on problems, solved and unsolved, and initiate future collaborations.'>
It is incredibly useful to meet other people doing similar things. It is nearly priceless to compare notes on problems, solved and unsolved, and initiate future collaborations.
</span></p>

<p>There are certainly attendees whose primary mission at a conference is to network. At times this can get a bit predatory, but in general it is a net positive.</p>

<p>Particularly in the open source community, finding that someone else has already solved a problem and is willing to share the solution could save days or weeks or more of developer time.</p>

<p>For a seasoned programmer looking for a job, this is a great way to feel out potential employers. Not only would I be hesitant to work as a programmer at a company that failed to value such events, developer conferences are a great way to be introduced to other employees of a company and see what they are working on. It opens the door to talking with these people directly about their work in a manner that is not easy in everyday business. In the case of an open source technology, conference attendance, sponsorship, and the contribution to sessions by an employer are all indicative of a company that contributes back to open source, values the community aspect, and fosters innovation.</p>

<h2>It&#8217;s Not All Rainbows, But It&#8217;s Close</h2>

<p>One major downside is that having someone stand in front of you and preach excitedly about their latest thing can, at times, be misleading.</p>

<p>This is not to say the speakers intentionally or negligently mislead, but each one often discusses the highlights of their new thing without strongly discussing the downsides. This makes sense as their intent at speaking at a conference is generally not purely to educate, but also to drum up support for their new thing or for publicity for their company or themselves. This results in many of the sessions having some kind of bias or marketing twist. This unsurprising as the speakers are often incentivized to do so and without such sponsorship most conferences would not exist, but it is necessary to remain cognizant of this facet when sitting in a session whose speakers claims are on par with claiming to have invented a better mouse trap.</p>

<p>Sometimes when I get back from a conference and decompress, I find myself thinking, &#8220;Wait, this only works in that specific instance? How is that even helpful?&#8221;</p>

<p><span class='pullquote-left' data-pullquote='Once the honeymoon period ends on some of these new things, it becomes apparent that instead of sliced bread, they&#8217;re just the same old bread repackaged in a shiny shell.'>
Once the honeymoon period ends on some of these new things, it becomes apparent that instead of sliced bread, they&#8217;re just the same old bread repackaged in a shiny shell. On the other hand, even the discovery that some of the newfangled technologies offer little benefits over tried and true methods can itself be a significant benefit.
</span></p>

<p>Further, while every new thing cannot itself be directly applicable and useful, each new thing that a developer learns is yet another thing they can add to their arsenal. Then sometime in the future, they will have the knowledge of how a problem was once solved and whether it would be useful in a given set of circumstances. So while it will not all bear fruit, gaining knowledge from a conference, as it does in any realm, serves to enrich the developer&#8217;s background for future endeavors.</p>

<p>If you are attending <a href="http://www.rubynation.org/">RubyNation 2012</a>, I hope to see you there!</p>

<p><a id="excitement1"></a>[1] I would <em>love</em> to attend DrupalCon this year, but the timing and travel just didn&#8217;t work out. Thankfully, <a href="http://www.rubynation.org/">RubyNation</a> is being held right in my backyard!</p>
]]><a href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/03/15/attending-rubynation-2012/"><strong>∮</strong></a><br /><br /></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Convert .png to .eps on a Mac]]></title>
    <link href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/03/13/convert-png-to-eps/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-13T22:31:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/03/13/convert-png-to-eps</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is one of those tips that seems almost too easy to be true.</p>

<p>My <a href="http://victorquinn.com/files/VQResumeLatest.pdf">resume</a> and cover letters are written in <a href="http://www.latex-project.org/">LaTeX</a>. LaTeX is a typesetting system often used for creating technical documents as it is particularly good at creating complex documents including scientific equations. I have been using it for a few years to draft documents both because it gives me a lot of control over the output and so that I could prepare myself for working with technical documents such as patents which are likely be written in LaTeX.</p>

<p>I wanted to include my signature in a cover letter. In order to do so in LaTeX, it required a graphic in <em>.eps</em> format. However, my signature was a <em>.png</em> image. I searched for awhile until I came across the answer which was so simple I felt silly for not knowing it.</p>

<p>I thought it may prove useful to someone else. This is a command line trick, so if you are not familiar with a terminal, this tip will not be of much help. Without further adieu:</p>

<p>Simply use the <em>convert</em> command line utility to convert it.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span>Convert Command</span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'><span class="nv">$ </span>convert image.png image.eps
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Yes, it was that easy! Out came a perfect .eps file which I was able to use in my LaTeX document. The <a href="http://man.cx/convert"><em>convert</em></a> command has all sorts of other options for resizing and many other things, but for simply doing a straight conversion, that was all!</p>

<p>Worth noting, while this worked for <em>.png</em> to <em>.eps</em>, it also works for <em>.jpg</em> to <em>.eps</em> and <em>.gif</em> to <em>.eps</em>. Have not tested anything else, but it appears to be pretty versatile!</p>
]]><a href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/03/13/convert-png-to-eps/"><strong>∮</strong></a><br /><br /></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yahoo sues Facebook for Patent Infringement]]></title>
    <link href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/03/13/yahoo-sues-facebook-for-patent-infringement/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-13T09:51:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/03/13/yahoo-sues-facebook-for-patent-infringement</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Wow. It will be interesting to see how this plays out.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2012/03/12/us-yahoo-facebook-lawsuit-idUSBRE82B18M20120312">link</a></p>
]]><a href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/03/13/yahoo-sues-facebook-for-patent-infringement/"><strong>∮</strong></a><br /><br /></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[fun.]]></title>
    <link href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/03/09/fun/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-09T08:23:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/03/09/fun</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Can&#8217;t stop listening to a band called <a href="http://www.ournameisfun.com/">fun.</a></p>

<p>Especially this song:</p>

<iframe width="390" height="80" src="http://rd.io/i/QVa2gjexPO4" frameborder="0"></iframe>

]]><a href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/03/09/fun/"><strong>∮</strong></a><br /><br /></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monster Menus and Drupal Multisite]]></title>
    <link href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/03/06/monster-menus-and-drupal-multisite/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-06T21:48:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/03/06/monster-menus-and-drupal-multisite</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Monster Menus</h2>

<p>Over my years working at <a href="https://www.amherst.edu">Amherst College</a>, I have been fortunate enough to have played a part in helping to develop and create a module for <a href="http://drupal.org">Drupal</a> called <a href="http://drupal.org/project/monster_menus">Monster Menus</a>. The module is a Monster! (pun intended)</p>

<p>The capabilities it adds to out of the box Drupal are quite incredible. It plugs many gaping holes in Drupal which made it suitable for use by a large institution such as Amherst College.</p>

<h3>Permissions gaps in core Drupal</h3>

<p>Out of the box, Drupal is quite limited in terms of its permission capabilities. It has a concept of roles which it uses for permissions. This is fine for many small sites or sites where there are limited content creators, but on a site with tens of thousands of users creating content, this starts to break down quickly.</p>

<p>In the simplest terms, Monster Menus layers, on top of the standard Drupal access permissions, a series of access permissions which approximate the permissions given to any modern filesystem.</p>

<p>For example, in any linux or unix based system, there are permissions such as read, write, execute which can be given to users and/or groups. This allows for very rich and nuanced access privileges such as John can edit this file but he cannot view this folder. View the screenshot below of the Monster Menus permissions interface for a given page:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://victorquinn.com/images/mm1.png"></p>

<p>As you can see, this is very similar to the permissions structure of a filesystem. As a result, this allows for things such as, &#8220;all instructors in the English department can edit the English department website&#8221; or &#8220;only John Doe can add content to this page and everyone can read it&#8221; or &#8220;John and members of the English department group can read this page but no one else can.&#8221; This kind of nuanced permissions is simply not available in off-the-shelf Drupal.</p>

<h3>The Approach Other Large Institutions Have Taken</h3>

<p>Many institutions have run into similar issues and have solved it a few different ways.</p>

<h4>Organic Groups</h4>

<p>The first is by using something called <a href="http://drupal.org/project/og">Organic Groups</a>.</p>

<p>It does add the concept of Groups to Drupal, but does not appropriately offer the nuanced permissions described above. For example, it would not allow for something such as &#8220;only members of the English department and John and members of the Philosophy department can edit this page.&#8221;</p>

<h4>Separate Drupal Instances and Subdomains</h4>

<p>The second is by creating an entirely different Drupal instance for each site and using subdomains.</p>

<p>This has many downsides, the most notable being that updating can be a monstrous pain.</p>

<p>At DrupalCon last year, I spoke with someone from another college that had ~160 different Drupal instances! They had a different instance for every single educational department in their large university. So they were trying to figure out a way to update the codebase in 160 directories and then run scripts to update 160 databases.</p>

<p>He was asking how other places dealt with the process of updating because it was almost a full-time job just for him to run around and update all of these separate instances. Ouch.</p>

<p>The other major downside is that, by using subdomains like english.college.edu or physics.college.edu is that, since they have different subdomains, they don&#8217;t share Google juice.</p>

<h3>Amherst College Paved Their Own Path</h3>

<p>As a result, when Amherst College wanted to adopt Drupal as their content management system, they needed a solution to deliver these kind of nuanced permissions and, since neither Organic Groups or these Separate Instances scaled, they decided to pave their own path.</p>

<p>Thus Monster Menus was born.</p>

<p>(<a href="http://drupal.org/project/monster_menus">Monster Menus</a> will likely get a broader treatment in a later blog post as I love discussing it!)</p>

<h2>Drupal Multisite</h2>

<p>One of the benefits of Drupal is that it can be set up in a multisite configuration. This allows multiple sites to share a single codebase which in turn leads to easier updates downstream. Having to only modify files once per server instead of once per website hosted on that server can be a huge time-saver.</p>

<p>However, as each Drupal instance in a multisite configuration shares the same code, they each have different databases so, for all intents and purposes, each one is an entirely separate and siloed site.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://victorquinn.com/images/mm2.png"></p>

<p>With this kind of configuration, on my web server I have a single instance of the Drupal codebase and, utilize a multisite configuration to have about a dozen different Drupal instances each with their own database. These sites each look like their own completely separate entities to the outside world (most notably because they have entirely different URLs), but under the hood they share a lot of the same codebase.</p>

<p>The primary developer of Monster Menus had the wise foresight to build in the capability to use it with a multisite configuration. His instructions can be found on Drupal&#8217;s website:</p>

<blockquote><p><a href="http://drupal.org/node/1366320">Multiple Drupal Sites with One Monster Menus Tree</a></p></blockquote>

<h2>Deploying Monster Menus with Drupal Multisite</h2>

<p>I have recently taken some time to work on some web projects for myself. Two of those projects were related and needed some nuanced permissions so I took it as a great opportunity to deploy Monster Menus (MM hereafter) in my own environment and try out the multisite capabilities to share users, permissions, etc. between the two.</p>

<p>So I followed <a href="http://drupal.org/node/1366320">the instructions</a>, installed MM on one instance, then using multisite created another instance, pointing it to use the same database. This leads to the following configuration:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://victorquinn.com/images/mm3.png"></p>

<p>This is when the problems started to arise. First, those instructions say in Step 1 that:</p>

<p>&#8220;During setup, it is important to note that you must use the same database for all of your instances.&#8221;</p>

<p>Hrm. This sounds like it could cause troubles down the line. Later:</p>

<p>&#8220;Choose the newly-created site in the &#8216;Current Homepage&#8217; column, and click the &#8216;Set the current homepage&#8217; button. Now, when you visit your site&#8217;s homepage, the page you just created will be displayed.&#8221;</p>

<p>Anyone familiar with databases will realize there is a problem here. If the two or more sites are sharing a single database, changing the current homepage as in the instructions necessarily also changes it in the other!</p>

<p>Unless I was missing something quite obvious, this wouldn&#8217;t work!</p>

<p>Now the primary developer for MM is an incredibly competent programmer so I assume he had some way around this. The instructions mention using the $conf variable in the settings.php file. Assumedly, since the current homepage is stored as a system variable in the variables table and $conf can be used to overwrite these values, it ought to be possible to use this somehow to redirect to a different homepage for each instance. First, I couldn&#8217;t figure out how to get that working, and second I noticed some other problems that wouldn&#8217;t be solved even if this worked.</p>

<h3>Other Problems With the Primary Multisite Method</h3>

<p>Since both instances share a single database, it impossible to set any settings on one that would not end up affecting the other. For example, changing the Site Name, E-mail address, Performance settings, and any other configuration setting on one site would change it the other! Unless there is a situation under which both sites have all of the same information and configuration, this setup would not work!</p>

<p>Sure, one could manually override $conf in the settings.php file in an attempt to account for some of these configuration changes, but it gets messy quickly.</p>

<p>Further, this method can only be used to override things in the variables table. It wouldn&#8217;t be any help for other database entries.</p>

<p>Things broke down more when it came to the use of modules. One of my sites was reasonably complex, requiring the installation of many modules. The other was relatively simple and I desired to keep it as light as possible. However, it was not possible to do this when they shared a single database! Installing a module on one instance necessarily installed it on the other due to their sharing. This introduced unnecessary bloat to the site I desired to be lighter.</p>

<p>The instructions mention using different database prefixes for tables not used by Monster Menus. However, this gets tedious for multiple reasons:</p>

<h4>Reason 1: Installing Modules is a mess</h4>

<p>The tables will not be created until a module is installed. So the process for installing a module ends up something like the following:</p>

<ol>
<li>Create a separate database for the non-shared tables</li>
<li>Install the module on the shared database</li>
<li>Dump and import those tables (and their data) from the shared database to the separate database</li>
<li>Create prefix entries for the instance that is using those to point to the separate database for those tables from the instance that will be using the tables outside of the shared instance</li>
<li>Uninstall the module on the shared database, setting its state back to before the module was installed.</li>
</ol>


<p>Note, this would simply break if there was an update to a module that added or removed a table because it&#8217;s prefix wouldn&#8217;t be in the list of prefixes. The person responsible for performing the module updates would therefore have to read through the module code, search for database updates, and pre-emptively set their prefixes in the settings.php file. If this is missed, the tables will be created on the shared database and will not make any sense.</p>

<h4>Reason 2: Difficult for standard Drupal tables</h4>

<p>This is difficult for more standard Drupal tables such as system where the entire instance relies heavily on it being set a certain way. Once it gets copied, moved, changed, there is a high probability of things breaking.</p>

<p>So this created many issues.</p>

<h2>Finding a Workaround</h2>

<p>First, I spent time trying to find a way to workaround this and get things to play nicely. The standard <a href="http://drupal.org/node/1366320">instructions</a> say that it&#8217;s possible to use different prefixes for tables not used by Monster Menus, but that they must share the same database and not have prefixes for Monster Menus specific tables.</p>

<p>So I could have manually created a separate database with separate tables and pointed my secondary instance at them. However, this would have the downside of requiring me to create any new table separately in another database as described above!</p>

<p>Put another way, this says that, by default, share all tables, only use different tables if we so specify.</p>

<p>The more I thought about this, the more it seemed backwards. I would much rather it default to using multiple, separate databases, with each instance using its own database tables, and only refer to the other instance&#8217;s database for any Monster Menus related tables. This way I can install modules, change settings, etc. on each instance without affecting the other. I envisioned some variation of the following:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://victorquinn.com/images/mm4.png"></p>

<h3>The Alternate Method for using Drupal Multisite with MM</h3>

<p>There is a very detailed post I made on drupal.org about how to do this. And I explain some of the background, but not in the kind of depth I have done in this post:</p>

<blockquote><p><a href="http://drupal.org/node/1471176">Multiple Drupal Sites with One MM Tree (alternate configuration)</a></p></blockquote>

<p>I won&#8217;t repeat the steps here as that would be needlessly redundant. The magic there though is that the multiple instances default to using their own databases and use the prefixes in the settings.php file to point to a master for any requests for Monster Menus specific content such as the tree itself, permission groups, monster menus blocks, etc.</p>

<p>This alleviates all of the issues with not being able to have different per-instance configurations, of having a different module stack on each site, and all of the other problems that come with requiring all instances to share a single database instance.</p>

<h3>Fringe Benefits</h3>

<p>Aside from simply remedying the issues described above, this also has corollary benefits.</p>

<p> A major one is that it is now possible to have a single master and X slaves. In my actual setup, I had only one master and one slave. However, as in my diagram above, it&#8217;s possible to have one master and two slaves. Or one master and fifty slaves. There is ultimately no limit.</p>

<p> And since they are all sharing the same Monster Menus permissions trees, this means Single Sign On is possible throughout the sites as a single user account is tied to permissions on multiple sites! It&#8217;s possible to assign permission groups from any site to any other site that is linked in this fashion.</p>

<p>And configuration on any given site (aside from the Monster Menus configuration of course!) can be entirely separate and siloed off from the others. Now if an administrator on one site changes the contact email or creates a new WYSIWYG profile or installs (or uninstalls) a module or changes the input filters, it will not break any content or configuration on any of the other linked sites.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p><a href="http://drupal.org/project/monster_menus">Monster Menus</a> is is an amazing module. Having the capability, with some tweaks like this, to share its assets and ablilities across multiple sites is unbelievably powerful.</p>

<p>Special thanks to <a href="https://www.amherst.edu">Amherst College</a> for paving the way with this module!</p>
]]><a href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/03/06/monster-menus-and-drupal-multisite/"><strong>∮</strong></a><br /><br /></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
