<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Miscellaneous | Victor Quinn]]></title>
  <link href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/categories/miscellaneous/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://victorquinn.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-23T15:40:34-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://victorquinn.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Victor Quinn]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[inquiries@victorquinn.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Convert .png to .eps on a Mac]]></title>
    <link href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/03/13/convert-png-to-eps/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-13T22:31:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/03/13/convert-png-to-eps</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is one of those tips that seems almost too easy to be true.</p>

<p>My <a href="http://victorquinn.com/files/VQResumeLatest.pdf">resume</a> and cover letters are written in <a href="http://www.latex-project.org/">LaTeX</a>. LaTeX is a typesetting system often used for creating technical documents as it is particularly good at creating complex documents including scientific equations. I have been using it for a few years to draft documents both because it gives me a lot of control over the output and so that I could prepare myself for working with technical documents such as patents which are likely be written in LaTeX.</p>

<p>I wanted to include my signature in a cover letter. In order to do so in LaTeX, it required a graphic in <em>.eps</em> format. However, my signature was a <em>.png</em> image. I searched for awhile until I came across the answer which was so simple I felt silly for not knowing it.</p>

<p>I thought it may prove useful to someone else. This is a command line trick, so if you are not familiar with a terminal, this tip will not be of much help. Without further adieu:</p>

<p>Simply use the <em>convert</em> command line utility to convert it.</p>

<p><code>bash Convert Command
$ convert image.png image.eps
</code></p>

<p>Yes, it was that easy! Out came a perfect .eps file which I was able to use in my LaTeX document. The <a href="http://man.cx/convert"><em>convert</em></a> command has all sorts of other options for resizing and many other things, but for simply doing a straight conversion, that was all!</p>

<p>Worth noting, while this worked for <em>.png</em> to <em>.eps</em>, it also works for <em>.jpg</em> to <em>.eps</em> and <em>.gif</em> to <em>.eps</em>. Have not tested anything else, but it appears to be pretty versatile!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
