<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Cloud9 | Victor Quinn]]></title>
  <link href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/categories/cloud9/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://victorquinn.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-06T18:07:59-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://victorquinn.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Victor Quinn]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[inquiries@victorquinn.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cloud9]]></title>
    <link href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/12/23/cloud9/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-23T15:19:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://victorquinn.com/blog/2012/12/23/cloud9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/cloud9.png"></p>

<p>I have been following <a href="http://c9.io">Cloud9</a> since their early
days. I was thrilled at their open source editor, <a href="http://ace.ajax.org">Ace</a>
(formerly Bespin) and actually wrote a
<a href="http://drupal.org/node/1377948">Drupal WYSIWYG plugin</a> to allow it as an option
for HTML editing in Drupal.</p>

<p>But, when I originally looked at Cloud9, as neat as it was to be able to edit
files in the cloud, it wasn't really too useful for much.</p>

<p>Just recently a co-worker sent me a link to some code he had written using it
with some client-side javascript code. It was nothing short of magical.</p>

<p>This. Changes. Everything.</p>

<p>Wondering what it'll be like to develop in the future? Just try out Cloud9.</p>

<h2>Direct git Integration</h2>

<p>Cloud9 can pair with your <a href="http://github.com">Github</a> or
<a href="http://bitbucket.com">Bitbucket</a> account and pull in all the code in any of your
repositories. So with just the click of a button you're up and running with your
code. That's pretty awesome.</p>

<p>But they actually had this awhile back when I tried it (though it now is even
more fluid and awesome). What has changed?</p>

<h2>The old problem</h2>

<p>Code editing in the cloud was neat and all, but I had to commit any changes I
made so I could check them out locally or on my webserver so I could test it and
see if it blew everything up or fixed the problem I was trying to solve.</p>

<p>This led to a tortured workflow involving committing sometimes not working code
in Cloud9, checking it out locally, running it, seeing if it worked or broke,
editing and bugfixing it locally, committing that, then going back to work in
Cloud9. As I'm sure you can imagine, Cloud9 quickly dropped out of my workflow
and I went back to just editing everything locally.</p>

<h2>The solution arrives!</h2>

<p>Imagine my surprise and wonder upon most recently checking out Cloud9 when it
had the ability to run code, in your browser! It can easily handle node.js,
rails, I'm sure more. It even handled this Jekyll-based blog with ease! In fact
I am editing this now, in Cloud9!</p>

<p>It has GUI shortcuts for things like git commands, npm install/uninstall, and
more, but it also allows you to drop directly into a terminal and run commands
there! It's just like having your own server with none of the headache.</p>

<h2>Always in sync across systems</h2>

<p>One of my favorite benefits of this approach is that everything is, by its
nature always in sync across systems. I can pick up my laptop, do some work,
then move to my desktop, open Cloud9 and everything is just as I left it. I
could go sit down in a random computer lab or library and still be in sync and
ready to roll.</p>

<p>This last bit, in my opinion, is the most powerful feature of this kind
of Cloud programming. For $0, I can have an always in sync IDE operable from any
browser, my own cloud server, and more. It took awhile for the gravity of this
to sink in, but this is pretty amazing. The barrier to entry for programming
with a server has never been lower</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>There's a lot more to discuss that I'm not touching on here, just wanted to hit
some of the quick highlights. I'm trying to work this into my workflow more so
I'm sure I'll have more thoughts later.</p>

<p>This is seriously awesome and feels like the future...</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
